

## **Hoang Phan**

**Business Analyst** 

Date of birth: Feb 16, 1996

Gender: Male

**Phone:** (+84) 32 656 2797

**Email:** hoangpm.qn96@gmail.com

Address: District 9, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Website: cv.hoangphan.win

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Business Analyst with one year of experience in analyzing, solving problems, and givingsolutions for foreign clients in catering to their needs for travel, news, booking, and trade centermanagement fields. I also had 8 months of working as a Quality control and 4 months of workingas a front-end freelancer.

My main responsibility is receiving basic requests from customers. Then, discuss with themtogether with my team that I'll be working with to further analyze, research and give the suitable proposals for them through UML diagrams, Business Process Modeling, examples, and the other document needs.

### **EDUCATION**

Aug 2014 - Jan 2019 Ho Chi Minh City University of Information Technology (UIT)

Major: Software Engineering

GPA: 7/10

Aug 2019 - Nov 2019 Colegio San Agustin - Language Skills Learning

Center, Philippines.

Major: English as Second Language Graduation Level: High Intermediate

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

### **Kyanon Digital**

**Business Analyst** 

I worked with Agile software development in all projects at KyanonDigital.

Main responsibilities:

- I gathered business and system requirements from the client; assisted and consulted the client in defining output requirements, formats, scopes of work and suggesting ideas.
- Research and give for the customer the wireframes and ideas of UI/UX.- Write "Agile user stories"; acceptance criteria; constructingworkflow charts and diagrams; writing specifications.
- Estimate workload with internal team, work with PM and PO todefine which sections will do first, the priorities of each task todeliver on time.
- Work with the Project team (Developers, QA/ QC) to review andtransfer requirements through the development life cycle.- Perform UAT to ensure that validated deliverables meet functionaland design specifications and requirements.
- Create User guide and Release note when the sprint ended.

- Have the meeting with customers to discuss and kick off the project
- Use SQL to verify data reports in CMS easier.
- Review and update the function specs of Crescent Mall management from colleagues.
- Write the report for testing to send to the customer every week.

### Aug 2017 - May 2018

#### **IMT** solutions, Vietnam

**Quality Control** 

I worked with Agile software development in all projects at IMTsolutions.

Main responsibilities:

- I created test cases and document for this website.
- Performing manual and automation testing to verify this website.
- Using the Jira tool to manage tasks; excel and google sheet tomanage test cases.
- Query database to verify a few functions related to calculation andrecord.

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

### Work as a Developer Freelancer with WordPress

Develop and custom a responsive blog with WordPress

- I met and recommended new features which my customer needed toimprove for his website.
- I created the tutorial videos which helped my customer easily to usehis website.
- I suggested to him using Trello and we managed tasks on it.
- Languages used: PHP, HTML, CSS.

### **ACTIVITIES**

### Oct 2014 - May 2017

#### University of Information Technology - Social Work Team

Team leader (May 2015 - May 2017)

- Organize weekly and annual volunteer events.
- Sharing and training soft skill to members of SWT.
- Organize a lot of Workshops for UIT students.

Nov 2015 - Oct 2018

# The Vietnamese Students'Association of the University of Information Technology.

Member of the Secretariat

- Organize events to students in Universities exchanged.
- Team leader of events at UIT: Love Winter (2015, 2016), Spring volunteer campaign 2016, Green summer volunteer campaign 2016, UIT leader 2017.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2019

- Certificate of Graduation in CSA - Language Skills Learning Center (CSA-LSLC), Bacolod CityPhilippines as a proficient English learner with a High Intermediate Level.

2014 - 2018

- Certificates of commendation of Ho Chi Minh Communist Youth Union and Ho Chi Minh Vietnam National Union of Student about

### **HONORS & AWARDS**

2014-2015	- Student with 5 good merits of Vietnamese Student's Association of
	UIT.

### **SKILLS**

Language	English (High Intermediate), Vietnamese (Native)
Business Analysis	BPMN, UML, Business Process Flow, Use case, UAT, ManagementRequirement Gathering, Build test plan and test report, Designwireframe, UI/UX Analyst, Brainstorming, Training
Project Management	Define Scope of Work
Methodologies	Agile, Waterfall
Tools	Draw.io, Balsamiq, Adobe XD, MS Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Photoshop, Jira, Trello, Asana
Professional	Decision Making, Effective communication, Self-motivation, Teamplayer

### **PROJECTS**

### OurBetterWorld and Travel.OurBetterWorld

(2018 - 2019)

Customer	Singapore International Foundation
Description	Our Better World is the digital storytelling initiative of the SingaporeInternational Foundation.
Team size	12
My position	Business Analyst
My responsibilities	<ul> <li>Analysis and design wireframe</li> <li>Gathered business and system requirements</li> <li>Define the scope of works</li> <li>Suggest ideas</li> <li>Review and transfer requirement to team members</li> <li>UAT</li> <li>Create release note and user guide</li> </ul>
Technologies used	- Draw.io, MS Office, Balsamiq, Adobe XD, Jira, Asana (tools) - Drupal

### **Crescent Mall Loyalty Application**

(2018 - 2018)

Customer	Private company
Description	Crescent Mall App on Google Play and App store help collect data from the customer and provide promotion information to them.
Team size	5
My position	Business Analyst and Quality Control
	- Discuss and kick off the project.

Technologies used	- Draw in MS Office Ralsamid Asana (tools)
My responsibilities	<ul> <li>Build a test plan and verify the quality of the project.</li> <li>Use SQL to verify data reports in CMS easier</li> <li>Suggest ideas</li> <li>Review and update the function specs</li> <li>Write the report for testing</li> </ul>

### JusCollege

(2017 - 2018)

Customer	JusTours
Description	Juscollege is a website which sells the tours for the students of Collegesin the USA, Canada, and Mexico.
Team size	9
My position	Quality Control
My responsibilities	- Created, manage test cases and document - Performing manual and automation testing Use SQL to verify data reports in CMS easier
Technologies used	- MS Office, Jira (tools) - Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

# Booking (Web and Apps), Veritas App & Jpay App. (2017 - 2018)

Customer	Private Customers
Description	Private
Team size	10 (every project)
My position	Quality Control
My responsibilities	<ul><li>Created, manage test cases and document</li><li>Performing manual testing.</li><li>Use SQL to verify data reports in CMS easier</li></ul>
Technologies used	- MS Office, TFS (tools) - Ruby on Rails, Objective C, PostgreSQL

### Worldsforus

(2018 - 2018)

Customer	Bjorn and Tram
Description	Worlds For Us share intimate stories, first-hand travel advice, music experiences and education materials that challenge the individual perspective and open doors to new horizons
Team size	2
My position	Front-end Developer, Quality Control and Consultants
My responsibilities	- Recommended new features - Set up website - Build a responsive blog - Performing manual testing.
Technologies used	- MS Office, Trello (tools) - Wordpress (PHP, HTML, CSS), MySQL